Saraba chikyuu yo, tabidatsu fune wa
Farewell Earth, a ship is taking off
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
A New Voyage
Space Battleship
Ucyuu no kanata Iskandar he unmei seoi ima tobitatsu
It's about to take off to Iscandar carrying the fate of humanity
Kanarazu koko he kaette kuru to
We'll return for sure
Te wo furu hito ni egao de kotae
Smile back at the people waving their hands
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
The Blue Crystal...
The color of that flower is the color of sorrow.
Sister, have you ever considered...
...giving up on your fruitless salvation efforts,
and opening up Sanktel instead ?
Wouldn't that bring peace to the universe ?
Humans always fight.
They can't seem to reach the same state that the creator, Archelias, had achieved.
In order for humans to
obtain eternity as they are...
...then we must rely on Sanktel.
That's what the Dezariam want.
It's the only way for humans
to be free from sorrow.
We still have time.
Please perform the ritual for Garmillas.
Yurisha, not much time has passed
since you became what you are.
Once enough time passes,
you'll understand that...
...with eternity in its hands,
mankind will not achieve salvation.
Eternity and happiness can never coexist.
You both already know that the humans
who currently inhabit this universe…
…were created by the intervention of the
Ancient Archelias civilization, am I correct ?
We are all children of Archelias.
Yet time of birth, and the time necessary
for us to grow and evolve differ.
Our personalities are different, as well.
The same goes for human siblings.
On that account, Iscandar is one of
the earliest civilizations to develop...
...much like the eldest son...
...having a tireless desire to improve
and a thirst for knowledge.
A greedy, controlling
and very selfish first son.
Because of that...
...the people of Iscandar realized early that...
...every rule of the universe would become
an obstacle in reaching the state of...
…the ancient people of Archelias, who
created us and then departed elsewhere.
Ranhalt...
Once you escape all physical
restraints, including this body...
Keyman, is that you ?!
Why are you here ?
What you're looking at is a human
form that both of you can recognize.
It appears an acceptable shape
must be chosen for the truth to be told.
What are you...?
Wait.
Scared ?
Right. I can't stop shaking.
Every Garmillas soldier seems disturbed...
...ever since they heard Starsha's
proclamation about telling us the truth.
It's like their bodies are telling them
that they shouldn't know about it.
Being in combat would be much better than this.
This is the entrance to Sanktel.
In order to proceed,
you must undergo a ritual.
Ritual ?
The civilization of Telezart reached the same
state as ours when they abandoned their bodies.
They obtained the crystallized entity called Teresa...
...but they became isolated because
of their intermediate existence.
The people of Iscandar are different.
We preserved everything within our memories...
...and obtained the ability to
change the universe with them.
This path is normally irreversible...
...but in your case you'll
only have a brief dream.
Don't be afraid.
Open your heart.
There are countless civilizations containing
the wisdom of multitudes of intelligent lives.
Every element of those planets, including Iscandar,
is stored in this gigantic memory vault called Sanktel.
Within those crystals, a number of memories
remain active, living on in eternal joy.
You did it, Susumu.
This male alpine black swallowtail
will complete your collection.
This butterfly can obtain eternity.
Once mounted, this butterfly
will remain beautiful forever.
But you know it, don't you ?
Such happiness won't last forever.
What if you could forget about everything
and live in this moment forever ?
What if you could live and re-live your favorite moment as many times as you wanted ?
Abelt, you are an incomplete human.
Everyone is incomplete.
That's why people kill each other,
even on the same planet.
Such twisted people are
scattered throughout the universe.
Humans annihilate each other, and they'll
inevitably bring destruction upon the universe.
Before that happens, we can turn entire
civilizations into memories for preservation.
Just like this butterfly retains its beauty...
...all living things can live in peace.
Multiple civilizations can
coexist forever in static time.
If we use the Cosmo Reverse System...
...we can even reconstruct a real
civilization from its memory.
That is, if we choose to abandon our eternal
happiness, and venture outside once more.
Now, let's begin the ritual.
Don't avert your eyes.
In order to store all the elements of a planet,
the civilization and its people...
...we must wipe them from the real world.
That is the ritual.
It's been repeated over and over to
preserve lives and civilizations forever.
Genocide by Iscandar.
You must be thinking something's wrong.
You're correct.
The people of Iscandar were the first
to turn themselves into elements.
It began with a few people.
And eventually everyone followed.
All except for the royal family,
which manages the memory vault...
...the people of Iscandar
abandoned their physical bodies...
...and laid themselves within Sanktel.
If so, who's performing the ritual of destroying lives and civilizations with a massive army ?
What was needed was a strong body, as well as the
weakness of surviving only in a specific environment.
Such slaves are easy to manipulate.
They must worship Iscandar as a god,
and follow its orders faithfully.
Iscandar discovered a planet...
...and abducted its blue-skinned locals...
...who were then forced to
migrate to Iscandar's twin planet.
Utilizing the Cosmo Reverse, the infertile planet was
reborn as an identical copy of their home planet.
The slaves are called...
...Garmillas.
In the ancient language of Iscandar it means...
..."Galman ape.""
Grow up quickly...
...Abelt.
Desler !
Knowing all this,
do you still wish to save me ?
It's so quiet.
It's almost creepy.
Will Captain Kodai bring Starsha...
I am certain he will bring her.
He isn't the kind of person
who would abandon someone.
The Garmillans are slaves who were
brought from Galman by Iscandar ?
Loyalty to Iscandar and the
pride in our noble blue skin...
...are just mere results of
mind control on the entire race.
The life of our planet was shortened...
...due to the stress of turning a lifeless planet into a copy of planet Galman thousands of years ago.
It eroded planet Garmillas
and hastened its death.
It was all to keep the
blue-skinned slaves in captivity.
It was a long time ago.
Iscandar closed the memory
vault thousands of years ago...
...and stopped turning lives
and civilizations into elements.
It's not because we
realized our mistakes.
We indulged in reliving the happiness of
the past and lost interest in outside worlds.
The evolution of all living things...
I redefined such Iscandarism,
a relic of the past...
...and tried to establish a new
relationship with Garmillas.
But you sought a planet to replace the dying Garmillas, and began an inter-galactic invasion.
It was the same path Iscandar went down...
...which is why...
...Earth became the subject of your relief, as it suffered the threat of extinction from the Garmillas invasion.
And then you sent information
about Planet Galman to us.
Why ?!
You once told me to grow up quickly !
Was it because you wanted
to tell me the truth ?!
Or to make me shoot you ?!
If so, you're beyond arrogant.
The Queen of Iscandar giving her
one life as repentance for past sins…
...won't settle as a recompense for the
oppression suffered by the people of Garmillas !
None of my actions are for redemption.
The reason why I tried to save Earth...
...and told you about Planet Galman
was simply to save myself.
I'm a descendant of Iscandar,
which self-righteously committed tyranny.
I'm also a member of the royal
family, which manages Sanktel.
I tried to ease my pain,
as I'm destined to live forever.
Aren't you the same ?
You're trying to save me to ease the pain and suffering of losing Planet Garmillas.
You can't atone for
anything by doing so.
We only needed each other
to console ourselves.
To live, means to continually change.
I learned that from your brother.
These collections of memories indulge themselves in happiness, and they refuse to change.
They're no different from being dead.
Dezariam is after the massive
amount of knowledge here.
These systems use the best
of those wave motion civilizations…
...and these can be made to
coalesce into a dreadful weapon.
We can't let them have it.
No matter what.
I'll surrender Iscandar...
...on one condition.
Let the Garmillas
migrant fleet escape safely...
...and hand it over to
the Earth-Garmillas joint fleet.
I accept.
I want to pay respect to your benevolence in trying to save all intelligent life forms.
Personal transmission from Captain Kodai.
Patch me through.
Yuki...Yuki...
I...I don't know...
...I don't know what to do any more.
What happened ?
Captain Kodai...
Kodai !
Once the Garmillas fleet escapes...
...Starsha will have Iscandar self-destruct.
Couldn't you force her to come ?!
That person's resolve…is firm.
Seriously ?!
Are you really alright with that ?!
A lovely image that still remains in my heart
ima mo kokoro ni nokoru itoshī omokage
A gentle smile shows through shining tears
hikaru namida no naka no yasashī hohoemi
Farewells are difficult,
but it's very important to have an end.
You have gone on a journey into distant space
haruka uchu no kanata tabidatte itta
As long as the memories
in Sanktel remain intact...
...we can regenerate our bodies
as many times as desired.
You man of love and courage…
ai to yuki no hito yo…
But such an existence is meaningless.
…I could never forget you, my dear
…wasureenu anata
You only live once.
That's why you foster a strong
will to find fulfillment in your life.
Like white petals called forth by the wind
kaze ni yoba reta shiroi hanabira no yo ni
A life ends when the time comes.
That's what life really is.
That's why I didn't revive
Sasha when she died for Earth.
Listen and believe in eternal love
towa no ai o shinji kiite
I reach out my hand to you !
te o sashinoberu watashi
The next time Sasha is reborn,
I want her to have a brand new life.
Is the sky getting dark…? Are you lonely…?
sora wa kuraidesu ka samishīdesu ka
I was going to give her name to a new life, which has
come into Iscandar for the first time in thousands of years.
But now, that won't come to pass.
I'm sorry, Yurisha.
You were hastily created from Sanktel so
we could interact with the people of Earth.
I don't think you understand
what I'm talking about.
I don't.
I don't...
...I don't, but...
Let me hold you like this for now.
My dear, I will never forget you, or the blue Earth
aoi chikyuu wo anata itsumo wasurenai de
With everlasting love in your heart, I'll live on !
towa no ai wo mune ni himete ikitsuzukemasu watashi
Resume transfer of Iscandar.
I'm sure I'll return...
kitto kaerimasune
...as long as there's love
ai aru kagiri
As long as there's love
Deusula III has reversed course !
Sorry.
It's alright.
You've lived your life
enough for other people.
You can do whatever you
want for the last time.
He can't be...?!
Desler Cannon, fire !
Abelt...
Abelt !
Kodai, shoot me !
Only its outer surface is special !
Fire your wave motion gun at my Deusula !
That'll surely trigger the destruction
of this fortress from the inside !
This is the only way, Kodai !
If we can destroy this fortress...
...Starsha won't need to have
the planet self-destruct.
I don't care if she's an illusion or if she's the
devil's pawn, who's toyed with the people of Garmillas.
I...
...love Starsha, you know.
Come about 180 degrees !
Kodai !
Captain Kodai !
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun !
The one to pull the trigger…
...will be me !
Iscandar, the Dying Planet of Sorrow
Episode 7
Hello, Sasha
Next Time
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Ryusuke Domon:
Miyako Kyozuka:
Miki Saijo:
Mikage Kiryu:
Mamoru Kodai:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Tasuku Hatanaka
Tomo Muranaka
Satomi Moriya
Eriko Nakamura
Mitsuru Miyamoto
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Gadel Talan:
Fomt Berger:
Elric Vam Desler:
Koichi Yamadera
Hiroshi Kamiya
Kotaro Nakamura
Junichi Suwabe
Kazuhiko Inoue
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Mœlders:
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Takaya Kuroda
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru